Arthur Juchereau

Gatineau, Quebec, Canada

arthur.juchereau.com

J +1 (438) 397 3992

Profile

Full-stack developer

Founder of MakeltHappen.dev

Former Head developer for the Canadian Research Chair of Digital textualities

Former CTO of LaunchLeap

Skillsets

Frontend: HTML5, CSS 2/3/4, JavaScript ES5/ES6/ES7, React (Nextjs/gatsby/vanilla)

Backend: Dedicated/Virtual server admistration (Linux), Mongo, Express, React stack, SQL/noSQL databases, Linux, Apache, MySql, PHP stack, SSL certifications

Audio/Video: Video transcoding, DSLR operation, audio/video/photo captation, Adobe suite, Studio/lighting setup

Entrepreneurship: MVP planning, Investor pitch, User Interview, Performance metrics, Idea gaging, Iterative development, Staff training

Links

ArthurBienSur (https://twitter.com/ArthurBienSur)

PookMook (https://github.com/PookMook)

Arthur BienSur (https://www.youtube.com/channel /UC1gv3EjkU9lrW_lPqAB8zow)

in in/arthurjuchereau (https://www.linkedin.com /in/arthurjuchereau/)

Languages

English (fluent)
French (native)
German (functionnal)

Work Experiences

Founder MakeltHappen.dev Platform to collect problems/ideas from users, create communities around them and find solution providers	Gatineau, Quebec, Canada
willing to help.	2019 - present
Head developer at the Canadian Research Chair of Digital Textualities	Montreal, Quebec,
Development of custom platforms for academics, used by hundreds of stakeholders in over 10 countries. This includes development in PHP/SQLite/HTML5 and Node.js/Sails/React/Redux and dealing with data files extensively like XML/JSON/YaML.	Canada 2014 - 2019
CTO Launchleap	Montreal,
Interactive surveys/crowdsourcing app. Development from the proof of concept to the fully-fledged self-served platform.	Quebec, Canada
Agile project management and training of IT staff. PHP/MySQL/HTML5/Linux dedicated servers.	2014 - 2017
Webmaster at Les Publications du Quartier Libre	Montreal,
Web administration of the student newspaper of the University of Montreal.	Quebec, Canada
offiversity of Montreal.	2013 - 2014
Technician at Canal+	Paris, France
Technician for the Canal+ French TV station. Cabling, Guest preparation and video recording	2011 - 2012
GameShow demonstrator, Sony Computer Entertainment Europe	Paris, France
Setup and logistic of Playstation European game show booths.	
Gamer feedback gathering and reporting.	2009 - 2010
Education	
Online class: Startup school	Remote
YCombinator	Summer 2019
Post graduate Diploma: Art, Creation and Technologies University of Montreal	Montreal, Quebec, Canada
	2013 - 2014
Master's: Network Architecture and Web development	Paris, France
Université Pierre et Marie Curie (Paris VI)	2010 - 2013
Bachelor's: Science and Web development	Paris, France
SUPINFO, The International Institute of Information Technology	2008 - 2010

Active Projects

Resume.is

Dynamic resume fetching data from a JSON file or API.

Made with Gatsby and now.sh

This resume (https://arthur.juchereau.com)

Source code (https://github.com/MakeItHappenDev/Resume.js)

Past Projects

MakeltHappen

MVP of a platform to collect problems from the users' daily life, and find solution providers to solve them. Deploying a platform with database and Server-Side Rendering on a serverless architecture. Using Nextis, Mongo Atlas, Zeit.co serverless.

✓ MakeltHappen.dev (https://makeithappen.dev)

Stylo

Online text processor for scholars, focused on metadata and scientific paper publishing. Exports in most formats used within the scientific community (XML, PDF, MD+YAML, LaTeX, etc). Made using Gatsby/react, Express/GraphQL, docker.

Used actively by about 100 researchers across the world.

Stylo (https://stylo.ecrituresnumeriques.ca)

Source code (https://github.com/EcrituresNumeriques/stylo)

Anthologia

Open database for the Palatine Anthology where anyone can view and add translations of the ancient greek texts, enrich metadata surrounding those texts.

Made using react, Sailsis, MongoDB and docker.

Used by around 100 contributors and serves a dozen projects fetching data from it.

Anthologia (https://anthologia.ecrituresnumeriques.ca)

Source code (https://github.com/EcrituresNumeriques/anthologie-API)

LaunchLeap

Crowdsourcing/survey platform.

Coded from scratch using PHP, HTML5/JQUERY (React for newer parts), MySQL.

Used by private/public organizations in Quebec for Insight Campaigns.

☑ LaunchLeap (https://launchleap.com)

Hobbies

Content creation

Photography and video recording

- Arthur | (https://www.flickr.com/people/arthur j/)
- Arthur BienSur (https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC1gv3EjkU9lrW_lPqAB8zow)
- ArthurBienSur (https://www.twitch.tv/arthurbiensur)

Board games

I always enjoy trying out new games, figuring out new systems. Super backer on kickstarter, mostly supporting board games.